# Sharvari A. Sangle

E-mail: sangl003@umn.edu

Portfolio: <a href="http://sangl003.github.io/Portfolio/">http://sangl003.github.io/Portfolio/</a>

Summary: 6 years of experience working as a GIS analyst in different environments and development platforms. Seeking a full-time position in a fast-paced, customer focused and challenging company to put to good use, and enhance my GIS skills.

Education Year Grade

Master of Geographic Information Science Fall 2016 GPA:3.72/4.0

University of Minnesota, Minneapolis

Bachelors of Engineering in Information Technology June 2011 GPA:3.7/4.0

University of Pune, India

## **Work Experience:**

SRF consulting Group: Jan 2017 – Till date

- Providing automation solutions for GIS analysis using Python scripting for Highway and transit network
- Development of ArcGIS Online map services and mobile applications and static cartographic maps for project areas communicating traffic and transportation characteristics to the clients.
- Support research and development of open source data analytics software stack including Alteryx, Tableau GeoMesa and Apache big data tools.
- Coordination with project managers and clients to plan, design, develop, deploy and maintain GIS solutions using custom or out-of-the-box tools.
- Integration of 3D city models built in InfraWorks with ESRI City Engine, including enhanced integration of real-time sensor data

#### Minnesota Department of Transportation - GIS Mapping Section

Sept 2016 - Dec 2016

- Cad to GIS migration along with cartography of City and county Maps
- Website updates and improvement

#### Summer Internship at U Services - University of Minnesota

June 2016 - Aug 2016

• Developing a 3 dimensional (3D) campus map viewer using ArcGIS pro and JavaScript API. Creating PDF maps & Map books for several departments in the university. Creating a Web App for visualizing Nitrate simulation.

#### Graduate Assistant at U Services, University of Minnesota

Aug 2015 - June 2016

- Creating cartographically pleasing pdf and web maps from spatial data and AutoCAD files, spatial analysis, creating
  Python tools for process automation. Developing web applications like Campus maps, Snow tow Heat maps, Genderneutral restroom data analysis, etc.
- GIS Data Curation, Managing ArcGIS Server and Data cataloging for the Enterprise geodatabase consisting of Terabytes of data.

# Summer Internship at U Services – University of Minnesota

June 2015 - Aug 2015

- Deliverable were Interactive Map Development, Technical Documentation, and Reflection paper.
- Study & provide potential options for the development of the Interactive map.
- Understanding database management, project requirements and customizing using JavaScript API HTML & CSS. Working with ArcGIS online templates and following University codes and standards.

#### Cybertech India - ESRI Technical Support Redlands CA (GIS Analyst)

Jan 2012-Jul 2013

- Providing technical assistance to internal and external clients for customizing the existing product, understanding
  gaps and achieving required functionalities.
- Mentored and trained fresh hires. Desktop SDK development with ArcObjects for .Net SDK , ArcGIS Engine, ArcGIS
  JavaScript API

#### **Technical Competency:**

- Languages: Python, VB.NET, C#, ASP.Net, C++, VB 6.0, SQL, HTML, ASP, XML,
- Database: PostgreSQL, SQL, Oracle 9i, GeoMesa, Hadoop
- Tools: Alteryx, Tableau, Visual Studio 2012, Python scripter, Adobe illustrator cc, Dreamweaver, Eclipse

## **GIS software:**

 ArcGIS Desktop (9.3, 10, 10.1, 10.3, 10.4, 10.5), ArcGIS Server Administration, PG-Admin, ERDAS Imagine, Terrasync, ArcPad 7.0, ArcGIS Pro, QGIS, ArcGIS online, Carto DB, ArcGIS Web AppBuilder, Trimble GPS device, GPS Garmin device,

## **GIS Developing platform:**

- ArcGIS Engine Developers Kit, Arc Object SDKs
- Python scripting, C# & VB.net
- JavaScript API, Google API, Leaflet, Bootstrap

# **Honors & Leadership Skills:**

- Volunteering at Courage Kenney Rehabilitation Institute 2015 2017.
- Volunteering at Nonprofit organization Minnesota Fringe Festival 2017
- Volunteering at Nonprofit organization Chance for them 2017
- Volunteering at Nonprofit organization BDS 2017
- Event leader for Robotics Workshop '11
- Lead actress of Firodiya Karandak (An intercollegiate Drama competition) '08.
- Women's Affinity Group Leader for cultural events in Polytechnic level '07.